Farnoush Farid

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Farnoush-Farid/c2c7822019a535d4

OBJECTIVE:

A challenging full time engineering position in a growth-oriented company to enhance my technical engineering skills while providing

mutual opportunities for development (Willing to relocate.)

CAREER INTEREST:

Oil & Gas Production & Exploration, Energy Monitoring/Analysis and Modeling, Design of Process Mechanical Piping and Distribution

Systems including Instrumentation and Controls, Environmental Remediation of Petroleum/Chemical Impacted Sites, Research &

Development on new thermal science management technologies or products, and Renewable Power Generation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher

Hazardous Chemical Risk Management Research - Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA - April 2012 to March 2013

Philadelphia, PA April 2012 - March 2013

Graduate Researcher - Conducted a survey of the general public in a number of US cities to document their concern and attitudes towards a hypothetical hazardous chemical release. The research involved collection and analysis of the data to determine what factors had the

strongest impact on the general public's decisions. The results then compared to a cost benefit model.

Research Intern

Biomechanics of Traumatic Aortic Rupture - Philadelphia, PA - June 2010 to August 2010

Philadelphia, PA June 2010 - August 2010

Research Intern - Analyzed the microscopic anatomy (histology) of the aorta wall after a traumatic injury using mechanistic experimental

numerical approaches. The research involved performing aorta tests to develop a physical and a finite element computer modeling of TAR in order to develop tools to predict the pattern of aorta injury in motor vehicle accident due to seat belts or deployment of airbags

Mechanical Engineer

Mapna Group - July 2008 to August 2009

Tehran, Iran Assigned to Power Piping Design Group. Under engineering supervision, participated in developing Process Flow

Diagrams (PFDs) and Process & Instrumentation Diagrams (P&IDs) for cooling tower piping system. Conducted basic pump sizing

calculations based on flow pressure losses in the piping.

Senior Design Project Team Member

Lathe Grinding Attachment - Eastern Mediterranean University - September 2007 to June 2008

Northern Cyprus September 2007 - June 2008

Senior Design Project Team Member - Worked as member of multi-disciplined engineering team to design, manufacture, and assemble a

Lathe Grinding Attachment for the M500 Lathe Machine available in the mechanical engineering department's workshop.

Energy Management Class Project Team Member

Lathe Grinding Attachment - Eastern Mediterranean University - September 2007 to January 2008

Northern Cyprus September 2007 - January 2008

Energy Management Class Project Team Member - The research involved study of worldwide energy consumption statistics in the building

industry, identify high energy usage sectors (i.e. cooling & heating, lighting, Appliance) and the potential new technologies to improve

energy efficiency and consumption. Performed a detailed energy audit of university campus main library.

Engineering Intern - Assigned to Instrumentation /Control Department

Tak Makaron Food Manufacturing Co - May 2007 to August 2007

Tehran, Iran May 2007 - August 2007 & May 2006 - August 2006

Engineering Intern - Assigned to Instrumentation /Control Department. Participated in programming and testing Programmable Logic

Controllers (PLCs) to automate and optimize the plant operation and production.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Environmental Engineering

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA September 2011 to March 2013

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Eastern Mediterranean University, Northern Cyprus 2004 to 2008

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS:

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point) Excellent writing and communication skills
- SolidWorks, AutoCAD, MATLAB, and LabVIEW Detail Oriented
- Strong organizational and planning skills Motivated and dedicated to learn new skills

JOURNAL PUBLICATION:

Michael Hamilton, Farnoush Farid, and Patrick L. Gurian, "Public Attitudes Toward Decontamination After a Hazardous Chemical

Incident", Risk Analysis (Under review)

AWARDS:

- -Drexel Dean's Fellowship, 2011 2013
- -Full Tuition Scholarship, Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus (TRNC) Government, 2004 2008 WORK AUTHRIZATION:

United States Permanent Resident